Vaishnavi Reddy

Portfolio Boston, MA | vaishu17sai@gmail.com | ₹ 7087743034 | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Summary

Full Stack Software Developer with 4+ years of expertise creating cloud infrastructure solutions and scalable, high-performing web apps. Proficiency in full-stack programming using backend and front-end tools like Python, JavaScript, React, and Node.js, as well as solid knowledge of API development, AWS and Azure cloud computing.

SKILL SETS AND TOOLS

Python (Flask, Django), R, Java, C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Angular, HTML, CSS, AWS (EC2, S3, Lambda, Kinesis, SQS, SNS, Step Functions), Azure (Data Factory, Azure Functions), Django, Relational Databases (MySQL, NOSQL, MongoDB,) Tableau, Redis, DevOps, Docker, Continuous Integration and Delivery (CI/CD) Kubernetes, Bash, Microsoft Excel, Shell Scripting, Jenkins, RESTful APIs, Agile Methodology, Scrum, SDLC, Git, GitLab, Jira, Leadership, Collaborative, Problem-solving, Communication Skills, Innovative, Teamwork.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

eBay, California

Full Stack Software Developer

September 2024-Present

- Built user-friendly, well-structured web applications leveraging React and TypeScript, improving user interaction.
- Implemented GraphQL APIs to streamline data retrieval, reducing server load by 15% and improving response times for client requests.
- Led the implementation of security features in cloud applications, ensuring compliance with AWS best practices and managed cloud networking solutions such as AWS VPC, subnets, and security groups.
- Integrated OAuth 2.0 for enhanced security and authorization, ensuring secure access management across various endpoints.

Fidelity Investments, Massachusetts

Full Stack Software Developer

April 2022-August 2024

- Utilized Python (Flask) and Node.js to design and construct backend systems, optimizing APIs for maximum performance and scalability.
- Created and managed automated cloud-provisioning solutions using Terraform in AWS and Azure by improving efficiency of 20%.
- Build responsive web interfaces using React by improving interaction speed by 30%, making a smooth and dynamic user experience.
- Managed MS SQL Databases and built complex queries, stored procedures and views using T-SQL for database optimization.

Proxforce, India

Software Engineer

December 2020-December 2021

- Constructed scalable backend systems using Node.js, integrated with MongoDB, by improving data processing capabilities by 30%.
- Implemented SSL certificates and encryption protocols, maintaining security across web applications and reducing sensitivity by 35%.
- Programmed test automation scripts in Python and Bash, enhancing coverage and reducing testing.
- Optimized cloud- based applications in Azure, using Azure functions for data processing and storage.

PROJECT

Walmart Sales Analysis- PowerBi and Excel

December 2024

- Developed an interactive Power BI dashboard to analyze Walmart's sales.
- Demonstrated expertise in data cleaning, visualized category and region-wise performance, highlighting key insights.

Bike Ride Sales Analysis – Tableau and Python

December 2024

- Completed a data analysis project on London bike usage using Python for preprocessing and Tableau for visualizations.
- Analyzed 1.55 million rides from January to March 2015, revealing seasonal patterns and the impact of weather on ridership.

CERTIFICATION

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate
Data Bricks Generative AI Fundamentals Certificate

December 2024 December 2024

Graduated: May 2023

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer and Information Sciences

New England College Henniker, NH

Bachelor of Technology

MREC Hyderabad, India Graduated: July 2021